# JEREMY DORAN

WEB DEVELOPER



+1 (860) 575-8694



jeremy.doran.95@gmail.com



46 Bridge St. Deep River, CT 06417

## **About Me**

I am a Connecticut native who has expertise in both mechanical and artistic backgrounds. I was a automotive technician and a aerospace equipment specialist as well as a videographer and classically trained dancer for many years, most of which were simultaneous. These skills lend themselves well to web development as databases and web structures require precision, where design requires an artistic eye.

## **Experience**

### Bauer Inc. 2020 - Present

Hydraulic / Electrical Assembly || Laser Specialist

Bauer consistently depends on me to fill many roles as I am ambitious and eager to grow. Currently, i travel for the company and build as well as maintain

#### Grossman Nissan 2016 - 2019

Auto Technician

Nissan entrusted me with becoming a factory trained, ASE certified technician. Considered an 'A tech', I was competent in the full gamut of repair process from diagnosis to heavy rebuilds and repairs.

## **Education**

#### 2013

Valley Regional **High School** 

In school, I excelled at mathematics as well as in design classes graduating as an honor student.

#### 2014

Porter & Chester **Institute** 

Graduated top of my class as an auto technician. I excelled at both the technical knowledge as well as the practical applications.

#### 2024

UConn Full Stack **Bootcamp** 

Covering a large sweep of software that is considered standard and current in the industry, as well as building industry connections.

## Languages

HTML Express

CSS MySQL

JavaScript MongoDB

React Sequelize ORM

RESTful APIs

GraphQL GIT

Node

## **Expertise**

- ui/ux
- visual design
- team development
- · growth mindset

## Reference

### Mark Auletta

Bauer Inc. COO

#### **Phone**

+1 (860) 583-9100

# Extended Experience

### Ekklesia Contemporary Ballet 2013 - 2016

Company Artist

Founding member of the company. I grew up on the attached ballet academy which I started doing at 9 years of age. Many travelling and performing opportunities accompanied this position.

#### ProTek Auto 2012 - 2014

Auto Technician

This is where i cut my teeth as a technician, specializing in European vehicle repair with a focus on Volvo and Saab vehicles. Here we used factory programming software to diagnose and repair vehicles often turned away by other shops due to complexity.

### **Ballet Hartford 2020 - Present**

Support Artist

Guest artist with Ballet Hartford, the highest caliber, CT based contemporary dance company. I continually support them with digital advertising and videography, as well as technical support.

### Snyder Civil Engineering 2019 - 2020

Fleet Manager / Engineering Support

Taken on as a fleet manager, I grew into engineering support both in the field with aiding waterline engineers as well as construction projects, as well as around the office with maintaining fleet vehicles.

## Solo Endevures

### Videography

Weddings / Performances / Product showcasing

I have found a passion in videography. With this, I have been able to create wedding memories as well as advertising material for dance performances as well as for my current employer's products. These videos are used internationally to showcace intricate aerospace equipment.

#### **Auto Repair**

All vehicle makes and models

My other passion mechanical repair. I have a small repair service that I maintain after hours and have been keeping active since my trade school days. I have personally enjoyed building and repairing many of my own vehicles as well throughout the years.